AI agents are shipping to production faster than any prior software category —
but the testing discipline traditional software earned over decades hasn't caught up.
This is AgentClinic. Every finding bound to evidence in the trace,
every result published natively into UiPath Test Cloud as the system of record.
Coach, not surveillance. Five minutes. Here's how it works.
This agent retried the same broken deploy four times. State hash unchanged,
no error log read in between. Seven thousand four hundred tokens, wasted.
A general-purpose LLM can describe this trace, but it can't tell you which event drove the verdict,
or verify its own claim.
What we need is an audit trail — and it needs to live in the release-gate system the team already uses.
Seven deterministic detectors, source-controlled.
Every finding must point at specific trace events as evidence —
a finding without an evidence span is a contract violation, rejected at the schema layer.
The score is reproducible: same trace, same rules, same number, every time.
Section five is the iron rule that matters most. When data is missing, we say so.
No guessing. No hallucination. The report admits exactly what it cannot judge —
that's how a clinic differs from a courtroom.
Same agent, this time triggered from Automation Cloud.
Same pipeline as the local runtime, but now writing the result straight into Test Manager.
One Test Case per pattern, reusable across runs.
One Test Set, one Execution per publish.
A per-pattern log with the evidence-bound reason visible right in the dialog the reviewer already uses.
The full markdown report attached.
Quality is no longer a late-stage checkpoint.
It's a continuous, governed capability — exactly the shape Track 3 is asking for.
Four roles, no overlap.
Judge is deterministic — the LLM cannot revise the verdict.
Coach rides UiPath's AgentHub LLM Gateway, so every LLM call stays inside the AI Trust Layer
for audit and PII redaction. No direct LLM provider API key.
Test Cloud is the system of record.
UiPath is the orchestration and governance layer that ties everything together.
The whole codebase was written by Claude Code over eleven days.
Every commit visible in the git log.
Repository public, MIT licensed, CI green, error matrix documented.
Drop a trace in, get an audit trail.
Thank you.